Guide to the James D. and Eleanor F. Newton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, Circa 1930-1990
  - Thomas A. Edison material in files
    - Letters to and from Mrs. Mina Edison (Box 5)
    - Newspaper articles on Mrs. Mina Edison (Box 5)
    - Letters to and from Charles Edison (Box 5)
    - Articles written by Charles Edison (Box 5)
    - Articles written about Charles Edison (Box 5)
    - Letters to and from Theodore Edison (Box 5)
    - Articles written by Theodore Edison (Box 5)
    - Magazine articles about Thomas Edison (Box 5)
    - Speeches and articles by Thomas Edison (Box 5)
    - Pageant of Light pamphlets (Box 6)
    - Pamphlets about Thomas Edison (Box 6)
    - Possible "Uncommon Friends" book material (4 folders) (Box 6)
    - Copies of autographed pages of books from Edison/family (Box 6)
  - Dr. Alexis Carrel material in files
    - Items received (Box 11)
    - Surgery and Life: The Extraordinary Career of Alexis Carrel by Theodore Malinin (Box 6)
    - Newspaper clippings & articles about Dr. Carrel (Box 6)
    - Letters from JDN to Dr. Carrel (Box 6)
    - Letters to JDN from various people about Dr. Carrel (Box 6)
    - Letters from Dr. Carrel to JDN (Box 6)
    - Letters to and from various people to Dr. Carrel (Box 6)
    - Letters to and from Miss Crutcher about Dr. Carrel to JDN (Box 6)
    - Letters to and from Anne Carrel to JDN (Box 6)
    - Telegrams to and from JDN to the Carrels (Box 6)
    - Magazine articles about Dr. Carrel
      - "Alexis Carrel—Contributions to Surgery" by Charles A. Hufnagel (Box 6)
      - "Organ Culture & Perfusion by the Carrel Method" by Theodore Malinin & CAL (Box 6)
      - "Alexis Carrel, as I Knew Him" by Albert Fischer (Box 6)
      - Time, 6/13/38, "Lindbergh, Carrel & Pump" (Box 6)
    - Articles by Dr. Carrel
      - "Prayer," 3 articles reprinted on booklet form from "Experimental Medicine" dated 9/1/26, 10/1/26, and 7/1/39 (Box 6)
      - "La Priere" (Box 6)
      - "Married Love" from Reader's Digest (Box 6)
      - "Breastfeeding for Babies" from Reader's Digest (Box 6)
    - Inventory of boxes of Dr. Carrel (Box 6)
    - Dr. Carrel papers—published (Box 6)
    - Dr. Carrel papers—unpublished (Box 6)
    - Georgetown papers collection (Box 7)
    - Georgetown pamphlets
      - "A Tribute to Alexis Carrel" by C A.L. (Georgetown Centennial pamphlet) (Box 7)
    - Copies of autographed pages of books by Dr. Carrel (Box 7)
    - Letters from Dr. Carrel to various people other than JDN (Box 7)
    - Papers: Meditation/Lourdes (Box 7)
    - Possible "Uncommon Friends" book material (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - Anecdotes (Box 7)
  - Harvey S. Firestone material in files
    - Copies of autographed pages of books from Firestone (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous letters and telegrams (Box 7)
    - Notes from Mrs. Idabelle Firestone (Box 7)
    - Letters to and from Harvey Firestone, Jr. & Sr. (Box 7)
    - Letters to and from Mr. and Mrs. Bud Firestone (Box 7)
    - Letters to and from Ray Firestone (Box 7)
    - Letters to and from Mr. Thomas (Box 7)
    - Newspaper articles about the Firestone family (Box 7)
    - Pamphlets (Akron non-skid magazines) and "School Days and School Mates of Harvey S. Firestone" and "The Firestone Story" (Box 7)
    - Possible "Uncommon Friends" book material (Box 7)
    - Anecdotes (Box 7)
    - Other Firestone material (Box 11)
  - Letters from Dr. Alexis Carrel to JDN
    - 1940 Oct 24 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Sep 28 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Sep 16 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Aug 6 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Aug 1 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Jul 23 (Box 11)
    - 1940 Apr 12 (Box 11)
    - April 2, 1940 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Nov 27 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Nov 20 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Oct 24 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Oct 13 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Oct 10 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Sep 27 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Sep 18 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Sep 15 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Sep 1 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Aug 24 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Jun 14 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Jun 10 (Box 11)
    - 1939 May 28 (Box 11)
    - 1939 May 6 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Mar 28 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Mar 27 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Mar 21 (Box 11)
    - 1939 Feb 4 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Dec 9 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Nov (Box 11)
    - 1938 Oct 17 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Oct 13 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Sep 27 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Sep 24 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Sep 23 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Jun 26 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Mar 17 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Feb 2 (Box 11)
    - 1938 Jan 22 (Box 11)
    - 1937 Nov 24 (Box 11)
    - 1937 Sep 10 (Box 11)
  - Letters from Madame Anne Carrel to JDN/EFN
    - January 22, 1938 (Box 11)
    - September 30, 1938 (Box 11)
    - March 28, 1939 (Box 11)
    - May 26, 1939 (Box 11)
    - June 30, 1945 (Box 11)
    - July 12, 1945 (Box 11)
    - November 25, 1945 (Box 11)
    - December 8, 1945 (Box 11)
    - December 21, 1945 (Box 11)
    - December 26, 1945 (Box 11)
    - January 11, 1946 (Box 11)
    - January 22, 1946 (Box 11)
    - February 1, 1946 (Box 11)
    - February 2, 1946 (Box 11)
    - February 9, 1946 (Box 11)
    - February 23, 1946 (Box 11)
    - March 13, 1946 (Box 11)
    - March 29, 1946 (Box 11)
    - April, 1946 (Box 11)
    - May 2, 1946 (Box 11)
    - May 6, 1946 (Box 11)
    - May 19, 1946 (Box 11)
    - September 10, 1946 (Box 11)
    - November 6, 1946 (Box 11)
    - November 8, 1946 (Box 11)
    - New Year, 1947 (Box 11)
    - June 23, 1947 (Box 11)
    - Christmas, 1947 (Box 11)
    - November 12, 1949 (Box 11)
    - December, 1949 (Box 11)
    - June 11, 1953 (Box 11)
    - April 19, 1956 (Box 11)
    - July 31, 1957 (Box 11)
    - December 28, 1961 (Box 11)
    - February 13, 1962 (Box 11)
    - March 14, 1962 (Box 11)
    - June 4, 1962 (Box 11)
    - July 26, 1962 (Box 11)
    - August 31, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Letters from Anne Lindbergh to James D. Newton and/or Ellie Newton
    - April 2, 1983 (Box 11)
    - February 24, 1982 (Box 11)
    - January 3, 1982 (Box 11)
    - January 13, 1981 (Box 11)
    - January 27, 1981 (Box 11)
    - November 19, 1980 (Box 11)
    - October 16, 1980 (Box 11)
    - August 31, 1980 (Box 11)
    - January 6, 1980 (Box 11)
    - July 3, 1979 (Box 11)
    - September 18, 1977 (Box 11)
    - August 30, 1977 (Box 11)
    - August 7, 1977 (Box 11)
    - April 27, 1977 (Box 11)
    - April 24, 1977 (Box 11)
    - March 21, 1977 (Box 11)
    - May 10, 1976 (Box 11)
    - October 22, 1976 (Box 11)
    - October 16, 1976 (Box 11)
    - December 3, 1976 (Box 11)
    - September 18, 1975 (Box 11)
    - August 24, 1975 (Box 11)
    - January 13, 1975 (Box 11)
    - August 10, 1974 (Box 11)
    - January 18, 1972 (Box 11)
    - October 24, 1971 (Box 11)
    - April 20, 1971 (Box 11)
    - December 17, 1967 (Box 11)
    - February 10, 1964 (Box 11)
    - December 18, 1962 (Box 11)
    - March 29, 1960 (Box 11)
    - August 11, 1955 (Box 11)
    - April 7, 1955 (Box 11)
    - March 25, 1952 (Box 11)
    - February 14, 1952 (Box 11)
    - April 7, 1950 (Box 11)
    - September 21, 1949 (Box 11)
    - April 5, 1948 (Box 11)
    - July 15, 1946 (Box 11)
    - October 22, 1945 (Box 11)
    - September 14, 1945 (Box 11)
    - June 30, 1945 (Box 11)
    - March 15, 1945 (Box 11)
    - February 8, 1945 (Box 11)
    - November 21, 1944 (Box 11)
    - November 9, 1944 (Box 11)
    - September 19, 1944 (Box 11)
    - September 5, 1944 (Box 11)
    - July 29, 1944 (Box 11)
    - July 3, 1944 (Box 11)
    - January 25, 1944 (Box 11)
    - January 1, 1944 (Box 11)
    - Christmas, 1943 (Box 11)
    - June 28, 1943 (Box 11)
    - June 8, 1943 (Box 11)
    - April 20, 1943 (Box 11)
    - April 13, 1943 (Box 11)
    - March 7, 1943 (Box 11)
    - March 5, 1943 (Box 11)
    - December 16, 1942 (Box 11)
    - February, 1942 (Box 11)
    - January 7, 1942 (Box 11)
    - December 29, 1941 (Box 11)
    - August 16, 1941 (Box 11)
    - March 28, 1941 (2 letters) (Box 11)
  - Letters from Charles A. Lindbergh to James D. Newton and/or Mrs. Ellie Newton
    - March 14, 1972 (Box 11)
    - October 24, 1971 (Box 11)
    - July 8, 1965 (Box 11)
    - December 19, 1964 (Box 11)
    - August 19, 1962 (Box 11)
    - November 15, 1961 (Box 11)
    - July 24, 1961 (Box 11)
    - April 14, 1961 (Box 11)
    - May 22, 1957 (Box 11)
    - April 19, 1955 (Box 11)
    - December 3, 1954 (Box 11)
    - February 22, 1953 (Box 11)
    - January 9, 1950 (Box 11)
    - June 27, 1949 (Box 11)
    - August 26, 1947 (Box 11)
    - April 29, 1945 (Box 11)
    - January 10, 1943 (Box 11)
    - December 5, 1942 (To Ma Newton) (Box 11)
    - May 21, 1942 (Box 11)
    - March 23, 1942 (Box 11)
    - April 15, 1941 (Box 11)
    - April 15, 1941 (To Ma Newton) (Box 11)
    - September 15, 1939 (note) (Box 11)
    - February 8, 1940 to Mrs. Newton (Box 11)
  - Letters from JDN and EFN to Charles and/or Anne Lindbergh
    - Undated—probably late 30's or early 40's (Box 11)
    - Undated—probably early 40's (Box 11)
    - Undated—probably 1943 (Box 11)
    - Fort Benning, Christmas Day—probably 1942 or 1943 (Box 11)
    - December 30, 1952 (Box 11)
    - February 11, 1954 (Box 11)
    - March 16, 1954 (Box 11)
    - March 27, 1961 (Box 11)
    - August, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Sunday, February 13, 1972 (Box 11)
    - Sunday, July 23, 1972 (Box 11)
    - September 2, 1974 (Box 11)
    - August, 1974 (from EFN to CAL in hospital) (Box 11)
  - Handwritten notes from Clara Ford to JDN and/or EFN
    - March 13, 1928 (Box 11)
    - January 2, 1943 (Box 11)
    - August 5, 1943 (Box 11)
    - January 7, 1944 (Box 11)
    - June 25, 1944 (Box 11)
    - January 2_(?), 1945 (Box 11)
    - February 28, 1946 (Box 11)
    - August 16, 1946 (Box 11)
    - August 28, 1947 (Box 11)
    - Other Ford material (Box 11)
  - Letters from Mrs. Mina Edison to JDN and/or EFN
    - December 30, 1944 (Box 11)
    - February 29, 1944 (Box 11)
    - January 23, 1944 (Box 11)
    - May 18, 1942 (Box 11)
    - October 12, 1941 (Box 11)
    - October 10, 1941 (Box 11)
    - September 2, 1941 (Box 11)
    - February 7, 1941 (Box 11)
    - December 29, 1939 (Box 11)
    - December 22, 1939 (Box 11)
    - December 31, 1934 (Box 11)
    - November 25, 1934 (Box 11)
    - April 9, 1934 (Box 11)
    - December 28, 1933 (Box 11)
    - December 12, 1929 (Box 11)
    - August 14, 1929 (Box 11)
    - February 4, 1928 (Box 11)
    - December 9, 1927 (Box 11)
    - September 19, 1927 (Box 11)
    - October 16, 1926 (Box 11)
    - Other Edison materials (Box 11)
  - Letters from James D. Newton to Dr. Alexis Carrel
    - September 1, 1940 (Box 11)
    - August 4, 1940 (Box 11)
    - May 22, 1940 (Box 11)
    - July 17, 1940 (Box 11)
    - June 4, 1940 (Box 11)
    - May 3, 1940 (Box 11)
    - September 28, 1939 (Box 11)
    - September 21, 1939 (Box 11)
    - June 7, 1939 (Box 11)
    - May, 1939 (Box 11)
    - March 22, 1939 (Box 11)
    - March 18, 1939 (Box 11)
    - December 18, 1938 (Box 11)
    - May 26, 1938 (Box 11)
    - March 2, 1938 (Box 11)
    - January 11, 1938 (Box 11)
    - December 17, 1937 (Box 11)
    - August 4, 1937 (Box 11)
    - August 22, 1937 (Box 11)
    - Other Carrel material (Box 11)
- Additional material, 1872-1993; Accession 1993-M-076
  - Correspondence, 1872-1993
    - General/family, 1878-1923 (Box 1)
      Primarily of Adelaide and Annie Napier; Eleanor Newton's first letter appears in 1914.
    - General/family, 1924-1931 March (Box 2)
    - General/family, 1931 April-1993, undated (Box 3)
    - Napier, Adelaide [with Eleanor Newton, daughter], 1917-1944, undated (Box 4)
    - Newton, James D. [with Eleanor Newton, wife], 1932-1992, undated (Box 5)
    - Whittemore, Roberta Forde [with Eleanor Newton, sister], 1917-1943, 1949, 1952-1990, undated (Box 6)
    - Diaries, travel journals, notebooks of inspirational thoughts, 1921-1943 (Box 7)
    - Diaries, travel journals, 1944-1949. 1959-1966, 1970-1975, undated (Box 8)
  - Subject files [with scattered correspondence], 1872-1992, undated
    - Autobiographical notes, Undated (Box 9)
    - Buchman, Frank, Undated (Box 9)
    - Caribbean films, contracts [7 folders], Undated (Box 9)
    - Certificates, personal, Undated (Box 9)
    - Couriers [girls' organization], 1926 (Box 9)
    - The Crowning Experience, Undated (Box 9)
    - Edison, Mina [Mrs. Thomas Edison], Undated (Box 9)
    - Finances, Undated (Box 9)
    - Forde, Thomas [father of Eleanor Newton], Undated (Box 9)
    - Holzwarth Ranch, Colorado, Undated (Box 9)
    - Lindbergh family, Undated (Box 9)
    - McDowell, Charles, Undated (Box 9)
    - Medical records, Undated (Box 9)
    - Memorabilia [2 folders], Undated (Box 9)
    - Memorials of friends, Undated (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous [fragments, notes, jottings], Undated (Box 9)
    - Moral Re-Armament, Inc. (MRA) [7 folders], Undated (Box 10)
      See also: Box 9. Buchman, Frank
    - Napier, Adelaide (Mrs. Thomas Forde), 1983, undated (Box 10)
      Biographies written by her daughters.
    - Napier, Adelaide (memorabilia), 1872-1886, undated (Box 10)
    - Napier, Alfred Milton, Undated (Box 10)
    - National Gallery of Art [Harris Whittemore Collection], Undated (Box 10)
    - New York School of Fine and Applied Art; Parsons, Frank Alva, Undated (Box 10)
    - Newspaper clippings, Undated (Box 10)
    - Newton, Jane, Undated (Box 10)
      Letters re her death and other letters.
    - Newton Associates, Inc., Undated (Box 10)
    - Northfield League, Undated (Box 10)
    - Oxford Group [6 folders], Undated (Box 10–11)
    - Photographs, Undated (Box 11)
    - Poetry of others, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
      Poems written for Ellie's birthday.
    - Princess Beatrix of Spain, 1959 (Box 11)
    - Shoemaker, Helen [memorial sculpture for Milton Napier Forde], 1973 (Box 11)
    - Shoemaker, Sam, Undated (Box 11)
    - Silver Lake, Adirondack Mountains, Undated (Box 11)
    - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander, Undated (Box 11)
    - South Africa/Oxford Group, 1927-1932 (Box 11)
    - Southwest Florida Professional Women's Association, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Travel ephemera, Undated (Box 11)
    - Up With People, Inc., Undated (Box 11)
    - Vandeweghe, Ernest and Mary (Box 11)
    - Vrooman, Carl/MRA (Box 11)
    - Warner, Olin Levi, Undated (Box 11)
      See also: Box 10. biography of Adelaide Napier.
    - Wedding of James and Eleanor Newton, 1943 March 7 (Box 11)
    - Whistler: inventory of etchings, Undated (Box 11)
    - Whittemore, Harris, Jr. and John Howard, Undated (Box 11)
    - Wishard, Van, 1991 (Box 11)
      Transcript of interview.
  - Writings, 1920-1992
    - Early years, Undated (Box 11)
    - Echoes of the Heart, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Prep for book of poetry, Undated (Box 11)
    - Famous Writers Schools, Florida [selections], Undated (Box 11)
    - Guidance of God, 1927, 1930 (Box 11)
    - I Always Wanted Adventure, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Works of other people [collected by Eleanor Newton], Undated (Box 11)
    - Yale Senior Prom [unidentified author], 1920 June 21 (Box 11)
- Additional Material, 1893, 1996; Accession 1997-M-074
  - Correspondence to Eleanor Newton from Fred Forde [grand nephew; re biographical information about Thomas Forde, Eleanor's father], 1996 (Box 1)
  - "Montreal Board of Trade-A-Souvenir" [photocopy of booklet containing information about Thomas Forde, contractor of the Board of Trade Building], 1893 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Undated; Accession 2000-M-125
  - Carrell, Alexis (Box 1)
  - Edison, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Avis (Box 1)
  - Ford home, Ft. Myers (Box 1)
  - Ford, Henry (Box 1)
  - Lindbergh, Charles (Box 1)
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow (Box 1)
  - Lindbergh, Jon (Box 1)
  - Land Lindbergh (Box 1)
  - Lindbergh, Reeve (Box 1)
  - Internal Revenue Service (Box 1)
  - Heroes (Box 1)
  - Newton, James D. [includes clippings about Newton and materials on Uncommon Friends Foundation] (Box 1)
  - Uncommon Friends [includes chapter drafts, outlines, correspondence with the publisher, reactions from friends, and clippings] (Box 2)
  - Newton, James D. [includes article and clippings about, anecdotes for Uncommon Friends, and printed materials on businesses] (Box 3)
  - St. Paul's Church, Akron, Ohio (Box 3)
  - Edison Park (Box 3)
  - Lindbergh Foundation (Box 3)
- Additional Material, 1980-2000; Accession 2005-M-026
  - Correspondence
    - Hunter, Willard, with Theodore Malinin, 1980, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Pyle, Homer, 1997 May 29 (Box 1)
  - Subject files
    - Newton, James
      - Eighty-fifth birthday, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Eighty-ninth birthday, 1994 (Box 1)
      - Ninety-third birthday, 1998 (Box 1)
      - Fiftieth wedding anniversary, 1993 (Box 1)
      - Eulogy, memorial service, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
      - Newspaper and magazine articles, 1990s (Box 1)
    - Uncommon Friends [includes correspondence with contributors, anecdotes, outlines, drafts, reviews], Circa 1980s (Box 1)
    - Uncommon Friends Foundation, 1996-1997 (Box 1)